<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-06-26T14:15:42+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">tamakoshi2001’s blog</title><subtitle>tamakoshi2001&apos;s blog for GSoC 2023</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Second post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/19/second-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Second post" /><published>2023-06-19T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-06-19T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/19/second%20post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/19/second-post.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="aplly-colorblind_safe-and-arrange-arguments">Aplly colorblind_safe and arrange arguments</h1>
<p>Hello. Today, I will introduce what I have been working on for the past two weeks.</p>

<h2 id="colorblind-safe">colorblind safe</h2>
<p>Firstly, it is about color settings. Previously, even when ‘qutip.settings.colorblind_safe=True,’ most functions did not have the capability to change colors. So, I have been modifying the functions to support this. You can see actual usage examples <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1LSNLWW2FBhX4PeMXJTxSN6Qgb-G6_TXn/view">here</a>. By simply setting ‘colorblind_safe=True,’ you can see that the colors are automatically changed.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/tamakoshi2001/tamakoshi2001.github.io/assets/72233550/f30373b4-4b6e-4e3b-a4a1-e51ea547cdda" width="300px" /><br />
colorblind_safe = False</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/tamakoshi2001/tamakoshi2001.github.io/assets/72233550/e5c1237a-b4b0-4c3c-a9a6-67e1ed66ed7c" width="300px" /><br />
colorblind_safe = True</p>

<h2 id="change-arguments">change arguments</h2>
<p>Next, I have been changing the variables in the functions. The issue with the previous functions can be seen by comparing the following two functions:</p>

<ol>
  <li>hinton
    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>def hinton(rho, xlabels=None, ylabels=None, title=None, ax=None, cmap=None,
        label_top=True, color_style="scaled"):
 """Draws a Hinton diagram for visualizing a density matrix or superoperator.
...
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>plot_wigner_sphere
    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>def plot_wigner_sphere(fig, ax, wigner, reflections):
 """Plots a coloured Bloch sphere.
...
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>By comparing these two functions, you can see the following: The first is that the order of arguments is different between the functions. The second is that there are arguments, such as ‘title,’ that are included in one but not the other. I am currently fixing this. Specifically, I am making the following modifications:</p>

<p>The variables are arranged in the order of mandatory variables specific to the function, optional variables specific to the function, and variables that are common to many functions. Additionally, I am removing arguments like ‘title’ that can be set later by the user. Here is the example of my change;</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>def hinton(rho, color_style="scaled", label_top=True, *,
           xticklabels=None, yticklabels=None, cmap=None, colorbar=True,
           figure=None, axes=None):
    """Draws a Hinton diagram for visualizing a density matrix or superoperator.
...
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>With these changes, I am confident that users will be able to use the functions consistently.</p>

<p>Currently, I am applying these modifications to as many functions as possible. I will inform you about the results in the next post.”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aplly colorblind_safe and arrange arguments Hello. Today, I will introduce what I have been working on for the past two weeks.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/06/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First post" /><published>2023-06-06T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-06-06T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/06/first%20post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/06/first-post.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="first-blog-of-my-contributions-to-qutip">First blog of my contributions to QuTiP</h1>
<p>Hi. My name is Yuji Tamakoshi. For the next three months, I will be updating my blog with my contributions to the Google Summer of Code (GSoC) project. I hope my blog will be helpful to someone in the near future!</p>

<h2 id="what-is-qutip">What is QuTiP?</h2>
<p>According to QuTiP website, QuTiP is an open-source software for simulating the dynamics of open quantum systems [1]. If you are interested in QuTiP after reading this blog, please check out the tutorials on the website and try them out on Google Colaboratory. Let’s experience the wonders and fascination of quantum systems together!</p>

<h2 id="overview-of-my-project">Overview of my project</h2>
<p>I will be focusing on improving the visualization capabilities of QuTiP. Visualization, such as graphs and animations, often helps people understand things better, and the same applies to understanding quantum mechanics.
The outline of my project is as follows: 
QuTiP already has several visualization functions, but they can sometimes be unfriendly to users due to unchangeable colors and disorganized arguments. This project aims to enhance these functions by unifying their interfaces and adding colorblind options. Additionally, I will develop an animation function for the evolution of quantum states. The final deliverables will include unified interfaces for plot functions with colorblind support, animation functions for the Result object, as well as pytests and documentation for all of these features.
You can find more details about <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1s66NPwtaFdaMp8p8nJi1qxfbzxhZyDW6Z6_aodu4sjw/edit?usp=sharing">my project</a> here.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-next">What is next?</h2>
<p>Currently, I am working on introducing a new class to make QuTiP more colorblind-friendly, and selecting function arguments to make them more intuitive for beginners. I will write them in my next blog post.</p>

<p>You can follow my current activities through <a href="https://github.com/qutip/qutip/pull/2170">this link</a>, and <a href="https://github.com/qutip/qutip/pull/2113">PR-2113</a> and <a href="https://github.com/qutip/qutip/pull/2120">PR-2120</a> are my contributions to QuTiP. If you are interested in contribution. See <a href="https://qutip.org/docs/latest/development/contributing.html">this</a> and try!</p>

<p>[1] https://qutip.org/</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[First blog of my contributions to QuTiP Hi. My name is Yuji Tamakoshi. For the next three months, I will be updating my blog with my contributions to the Google Summer of Code (GSoC) project. I hope my blog will be helpful to someone in the near future!]]></summary></entry></feed>